GOKUL KALYANARAMAN

Sr. User Experience Designer

gokulkalyanaraman@gmail.com | +91-9884-118-164 | Chennai, INDIA

View Portfolio | Password: 112233

User Experience Designer with 6 years of experience in delivering efficient and feasible UX solutions across Banking, Travel, Automobile and Ecommerce domains. I bring deep knowledge in Strategy and Design across different platforms including Web and iOS.

SKILLS

- Expert knowledge of Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Balsamiq
- Ability to create wireframes from concept to completion
- Strong hands-on visual design skill
- Strong verbal and written communication skills
- Attention to detail and strong usability intuition, along with rapid prototyping
- Experience leading small teams and delivering UX projects
- Experience conducting stakeholder meetings efficiently

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Citicorp Services India Pvt. Ltd.

(May 2014 – Till Date)

Profile: Senior UX Designer Consultant (From Pixint)

- Leading the design team for a global risk management portal called *Citi-Insight*, which achieved common user experience across 150+ applications by building UI/UX Standards and Guidelines.
- Strategized and designed the complete UX and UI for a Risk reporting application called
 CitiARC, which became the tool to monitor the firm's performance for the senior
 executives.
- Redesigned a compliance / assessments survey tool called eCAMP, resulting in increased number of users and improved data quality.

Pixint Graphics Pvt. Ltd.

(May 2013 – Till Date)

Profile: Senior UX Designer Consultant

- Lead the team of designers and developers to deliver a TV navigable application for Vantage Deluxe World Travel. This TV app became the one-stop-shop for the Vantage's guests to avail all the facilities ranging from room service, itinerary, music, movies, shopping, etc. available during their voyage.
- Designed the web and mobile portal for **Neeyamo**, a recruitment agency, resulting in improved visit-to-query conversion rate.
- Designed Harley Davidson Dealers Go Guide website to bring Harley Davidson riders together in the US. This website attracted over 4000 users within 12 months since its inception.
- Redesigned the UI of the inventory management application for **Nathan Trotter** (tin manufacturer), mainly to equip the users to perform bulk operations. This resulted in saving 2/3rd of the time of inventory managers. This application was later rebranded and renamed to **TinTech** by the company and is offered in the open market.

Fox Star Production (Chennai)

(Nov 2012- May 2013)

Profile: Junior Assistant Director

- o Involved in movie discussions, auditions, location scout at different levels inside the agency under director **A.R.Murugadoss'** leadership.
- o Contributed in the art direction department to design digital artifacts for the filming of the movie **Maatraan**.
- Wrote and directed a Tamil short film called *Vazhendhen Vazhamal*, which made it to the top 10 in **Chennai Short Film Gala**, which had 200+ entries.

Galatta Media

(Oct 2011 – Nov 2012)

Profile: Junior Content Writer

o Started out as a fresher in the English South Indian film magazine where I worked on articles, reviews and celebrity interviews.

EDUCATION

BSc in Visual Communication (2011)

St. Thomas College of Arts and Science, Chennai, INDIA. Affiliated to University of Madras, INDIA.

Diploma in Information Technology (2008)

St. Michaels Polytechnic College, Chennai, INDIA. Affiliated to Directorate of Technical Education (DOTE), INDIA.

o Class 10th (2005)

Dr. Nalli Kuppuswami Vivekananda Vidyalya, Chennai, INDIA Affiliated to Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE), INDIA.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 29 October, 1990

Nationality: Indian

Languages: English, Tamil

With 4 years of experience in core UX / UI designing, I assure you that I will consistently produce quality work.